Finding Aid for the Frank Lawrence Owsley Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Research Materials
  - King Cotton Diplomacy
    - Notecards
      - List—Names of Foreign Ministers, Librarians, Consuls, etc. (Box 30, Folder 10)
Peoples, James A., 1933; re: article on Scottsboro.
Perry, Charles D. (2), 1951, 1952; re: Pharr's Aeneid.
Petrie, George (9), 1915-42; re: recommendations and writings, reminiscences.
Pharr, Clyde, 1945; re: Theodosian Code.
Phillips, Ulrich B., 1903 to Henry; re: reasons for going to Wisconsin and hopes to produce something noteworthy on history of South.
Pickens, W. E., Jr., 1956; re: social security regulations.
Pierce, Bessie L. (2), 1935, 41; re: presentation of Dodd volume and her research.
Pi Gamma Mu, 1925; re: membership.
Pipkin, Charles W. (2), 1934; re: writings for Southern Review.
Pomfret, John E. (8), 1936-45; re: Social Science Research grants and others; reprint of article.
Posey, Walter B. (2), 1934, 1952; re: review and graduate students.
Pruitt, Maurice (3); 1954-56; re: experiences in armed forces and historical characters.
Ramsdell, Charles W. (5), 1935-36; re: programs of SHA, Lincoln and Fort Sumter, state socialism in the Confederacy, etc.
Ramsey, John (4), 1953; re: University of Alabama History Department.
Rand McNally & Co., 1956; re: selections from King Cotton.
Randall, J. G. (2), 1945; re: comments on book; reprint of article on settlement of Southern frontier.
*Rawe, John C., S. J., 1937; re: farm tenancy and agrarianism.
Reeves, Ada M., 1935; re: speech to Colonial Dames.
Regen, W. D., Jr., 1942; re: armed services.
Reynolds, T. H., 1936; re: program of SSSA
Reynolds, Wade (5), n.d., 1949; re: teaching, writing, etc.
Rhodes, M. C., 1952; re: teaching position.
Rice, Nannie H. (2), 1951; re: Walker genealogy.
Rich, Dr. Celia, 1949; re: Plain Folk.
Richardson, Patrick W. (2), 1952; re: paper to Huntsville Historical Society.
Richardson, W. C., 1953; re: recommendation.
Rippa, Sol Alexander (2), 1952, 1955; re: Ford Fellowship.
Rippy, J. Fred (7), 1925-55; re: review of State Rights; Archivist of U.S., program of American Historical Association; conditions at Chicago in 1955.
Robert, Joseph C. (2), 1944-45; re: program and reprint.
Roberts, Frances (10), 1951-54; re: graduate work and writings at University of Alabama.
Robertson, J. Fall, 1954; re: daughter Nancy.
Robinson, Janie Grace, 1952; re: writings of father.
Robinson, William M. (3), 1935-37; re: program and writings on Confederate Judiciary.
Robinton, Madeline, 1939; re: Prize Court decisions.
Robison, Dan M. (4), 1950-54; re: Plain Folk reprint, position with TSLA, Tennessee Historical Quarterly.
Ross, Letitia D., 1951; re: new position.
Rowland, Donald W., 1951; re: summer teaching position.
Rutland, J. R., 1942; re: genealogy, Dr. Petrie and English instructors.
Ryle, Walter H. (2), 1934; re: dissertation and recommendation for Social Science position.
Samford, Thomas, n.d.; re: Battle of Shiloh.
Sarratt, Madison, 1949; re: Vanderbilt's loss of Frank Owsley.
Savage, Ernest C. (3), 1931-32; re: writings on Civil War.
Schlesinger, A, M., 1940; re: request for reprint of "Economic Basis of Society," etc.
Schmidt, L. B., 1941; re: presidential address and other writings.
Schmitt, Bernadotte E. (5), 1926-351 re: "Defeatism in Confederacy" and festschrift for Dodd.
Shannon, Fred A. (2), 1940-42; re: reprints
*Shryock, Richard H. (3), 1936-40; re: grants and writings on Southern history.
Shugg, Roger W, (3), 1950-55; re: proposed writing.
Shumate, Thomas D., 1953; re: new position.
*Silver, James W. (12), 1936-55; re: teaching positions; big business, big labor, politics, writings, programs, etc.
Simms, Henry H., 1934; re: review of Cole's book.
Simms, LeRoy A., Sterling J. Foster, and Clyde W. Ennis, 1933; re: "Scottsboro -- The Third Crusade."
Simpkins, Francis B. (2), 1951, 1953; re: student; and program of SHA
*Simpson, Albert (16), 1935-53; re: farmer's situation in 1935, Pillars of Agrarianism, teaching positions, dissertation, SHA meeting in Charleston, Presidential address, Georgia history, work at Maxwell Field; World War II, work with Historical Division, Army Air Force; Negro problem.
Skipper, Otis C. (25), 1940-54; re: programs and meetings of SHA, biography of DeBow.
Smith, Charles E., 1949; re: Plain Folk.
Smith, Culver H., 1934; re: AHA meeting.
Smith, James Anderson, 1945; re: King Cotton Diplomacy.
Smith, Louis (2), 1934, 1950; re: graduate work and teaching positions.
Smith, T. Lynn (3), 1950-55; re: volume on Brazil and The Peoples of Latin America.
Smith, Warren Irving (15), 1950-56; re: dissertation and teaching positions.
Social Science Research Council (13), 1930-44; re: programs and grants.
South, Percy (3), 1945-49; re: dissertation on land tenure in Montgomery County, Alabama.
Southard, Shelby E. (2), 1939; re: graduate work.
Spengler, Joseph J. (2), 1937, 1940; re: reprint on "Economic Basis of Society," etc.
Sprigg, Earle F., 1953; re: admiralty records at Key West.
Stanley, C. M., 1954; re: "The Education of a Southern Girl."
Stanton, William A., 1945; re: John Brown and Kansas.
Staples, Thomas S, (3), 1934-39; re: teaching position, SHA program, and Roosevelt.
Stevens, George, 1935; re: review for The Saturday Review of the Lamar book.
*Stephenson, Wendell H. (14), 1935-53; re: book reviews for Journal of Southern History; articles for publication; teaching techniques; dissertations.
Sterkx, Gene (9), 1953-56; re: teaching positions, dissertation, etc.
*Stewart, Edward Bay (8), 1935-37; re: farm tenancy, agrarianism, and articles in American Review.
Stewart, John Craig, 1955, to Gordon Chappell; re: fourth-grade textbook on Alabama.
Stewart, Randall (2), 1956; re: Fugitive Reunion.
Stockdale, William, 1949; re: Phi Alpha Theta membership.
Stocking, George W. (3); 1947-49; re: summer grants, etc.
*Stone, Geoffrey (4), 1936-51: re: The Examiner, and the lack of a periodical representing the point of view of the American conservative.
Strode, Hudson, 1955; re: volume on Jefferson Davis.
Sulzby, James F. (3), 1948-49; re: speeches to Alabama Historical Association.
Summersell, Charles G. (17), 1942-56; re: recommendations and history department at University of Alabama.
*Swint, Henry Lee (33); 1933-56; re: graduate work, army service, segregation. and integration, teaching positions, politics, etc.
*Sydnor, Charles S. (9), 1937-50; re: SHA, recommendation to Social Science Research Council, historical writings on Southern yeomen, and appreciation for review.
Talman, James J., 1941; re: writings in Southern history.
Tansill, Charles G., 1946; re: book on Bayard.
*Tate, Allen (22), 1928-55; re: Who Owns America; agrarians, writings, Negro problem, speech at U. of A., etc.
ten Hoor, Martin (19); 1948-56; re: decision to come to U. of A., Operation Bootstrap, discussion of successor as head of History Department, various Department problems, approval of leave.
Terry, Benjamin, 1919; re: recommendation.
Thach, Charles C., 1913; re: letter of recommendation.
Thach, Harry S., 1941; re: fellowship at Vanderbilt.
Thach, Mrs. Charles C. (4), 1941; re: son Harry Thach.
Thomas, Alfred H., 1951; re: congratulations on promotion.
Thomas, Dan H, (2), 1934, 1953; re: teaching positions, writings, etc.
Thomas, David, 1933; re: King Cotton Diplomacy.
Thompson, Brooks and Hariett, 1954-55; re: dissertation and teaching positions.
Thompson, S. B., 1937; re: teaching positions.
Thompson, Scerial, 1952, 1953; re: writings.
Thrasher, James D., 1950: re: accident and failure to return to Graduate School.
Tidwell, R. E., 1924; re: teaching position.
Tilley, Nannie M. (2), 1940, 1950; re: Barnsley papers and recommendations.
Todd, Herbert H. (2), 1934-35; re: teaching positions, dissertation etc.
Todd, L. O., 1954; re: writings.
Toner, Ethel Fowlkes (2), 1953; re: Colonial Dames recommendation regarding study of American History.
Truett, Randle B. (4), 1936-45; re: work with Department of Interior's National Park Service, etc.
Tucker, William H., 1953; re: historical research.
Turner, Hill, 1949; re: Plain Folk.
Tyler, Sue Ruffin (Mrs. Lyon G.) (2), 1936; re: article for Tyler's Quarterly.
Van Auken, Sheldon (4), 1953; re: dissertation at Oxford.
*Vance, Rupert B., 1935; re: agrarianism.
Vandiver, Frank (2), 1948, 1953; re: recommendation etc.
Van Sickle, John, 1943; re: reprint on economic structure.
Venable Austin L. (17), 1935-54; re: teaching positions.
Vipond, Herbert E., 1920; re: death of George.
Virginia History Committee (Mary D. Carter), 1936; re: work the the Committee enclosing letters of George B. McClellan, Charles W. Ramsdell, E. L. Masters, Claude G. Bowers, and Lloyd F. Wagner.
Virginia Quarterly Review (12), 1942-49; re: book reviews and other writings.
Volwiler, A. T., 1934; re: speech on "Three American Crusades."
*Wade, John Donald (13), 1934-47; re: speech at University of Georgia, Georgia Review.
Walker, Curtis H. (7), 1950-54; re: Eleanor of Aquitaine, Plain Folk, etc.
Walker, Harry J., n.d.; re: address on WSM.
Wall, Bennett H. (2), 1953; re: membership in SHA.
Wallace, Mary Barbour, 1934; re: speech to Colonial Dames.
Wallace, Sarah Agnes, 1950; re: review of Benjamin Horan.
Waller, George M., 1954; re: manuscript.
Walser, Zeb V., 1926; re: State Rights in the Confederacy.
*Walters, Bennett (26), 1946-56; re: research, dissertation, W. T. Sherman, Emory and Henry, teaching positions, Vanderbilt, Alabama, Negroes, etc.
Watson, Elliott O., 1934; 1935; re: graduate work.
*Warren, Robert Penn (43); 1933-55; re: writings for Southern Review, literary criticism, poetry, etc.
Weaver, Blanche Henry Clark (3), n.d.; re: dissertation and other writings (numerous other letters to Harriet Owsley)
*Weaver, Herbert (27); 1941-54; re: dissertation, armed services, land tenure studies attacked, publication of Mississippi Farmers, Air Force Historical Division.
Weber, Bernerd C., 1953; re: salary.
Welker, Robert, 1952; re: visit.
Wertenbaker, Thomas J. (2), 1940-4l; re: reprints.
West, Richard S. (6), 1942-44; re: King Cotton Diplomacy, writings, recommendations, Gideon Welles, reviews, etc.
Westwood House School, 1956; re: Margaret's attendance.
Wilber, Leon A., 1954; re: teaching position.
Wiley, Bell I. (13), 1942-50; re: program of SHA, Fleming Lecturer, program for lectures, publication of Plain Folk, reviews, etc.
Wilkerson, Marcus W. (7), 1942-52; re: publication of Plain Folk.
Williams, Charlotte, 1941.
Williams, Clanton W. (19), 1935-55; re: McGehees, graduate work, dissertation Air War College, Operation Bootstrap, University of Houston.
Williams, C. E., 1949; re: summer school.
Williams, Ernest G., 1952; re: speech of No Yong Park.
Williams, Frank B., 1951; re: grant-in-aid.
Williams, Ralph R., 1954; re: teaching position.
Williams, T. Harry, 1948; re: Fleming lectures.
Williams, William Appleman, n.d.; re: selection from King Cotton Diplomacy.
Windham, William T. (5), 1952-55; re: dissertation, teaching positions.
Winn, Frederick G. (2), 1951, 1952; re: doctoral dissertation on diplimatic history.
*Winters, Curtis R. (2), 1933; re: The Third Crusade and I'll Take My Stand, sectionalism.
Wirth, Fremont P. (3), 1950-54; re: writings and recommendations.
Woodward, G. Vann (2), 1940, 1952; re: program of S.H.A., fellowships at Johns Hopkins.
Woody, Robert H. (3), 1936-37; re: programs, writings, etc.
Wuorinen, John H. (5), 1954-55; re: summer teaching at Columbia, writings, etc.
Yale Review (5), 1935-40; re: writings for the Review.
Yates, Richard E. (Dick) (13), 1936-49; re: teaching position, writings, Hendrix College, personal problems, dissertation on Vance.
*Young, Stark (4), 1936; re: McGehee's, selection of writings, etc.
Younger, Edward, 1952; re: nominating committee of SHA.
ADDENDUM TO THE FRANK OWSLEY PAPERS (incoming correspondence)
BROCK, W.R. (2) 1956; re: position at Selwyn College, Cambridge and accomodations for family in Cambridge
CARR, S.H. (1) 1956; re: accomodations in Cambridge
CLARK, ADRIAN N., Vice-President of Van Nostrand (2); re: Owsley's appraisal of a ms. and revision of a history book
CLARK, ALDEN H., Vice-President of Henry Holt & Co. (2) 1956; ret publication of history book
COHEN, RUTH (1) 1956; re: daughter's schooling in Cambridge
DENBO, BRUCE F., of Louisiana State U. Press (1) 1949; re: Owsley's book Plain Folk
FAIN, TYREE (1) 1956; re: request for recommendation
GOWER HERSCHEL (4) 1955-1956; re: Fulbright recommendation, Agrarian news, house in Cambridge Owsley will rent
JORDAN, BILL, former student (3) 1956; re: congradulations on Fulbright and thank yours for Owsley's recommendations
MOE, HENRY ALLEN (1) 1956; re: request for Guggenheim applicants
MOORE, A.B. (1) 1956 re: bill passing to create National Military Park
MUMFORD, D.E. (1) 1956; re: schooling for daughter in Cambridge
MURRAY, A.R. (1) 1956; re: schooling for daughter in Cambridge
OWSLEY, HARRIET C, (1) n.d.; re: post card filling Owsley in on his mail
PEACE, K.M. (1) 1956: re: schooling for daughter in Cambridge
PETRIE, GEORGE (1) 1919; re: recommendation on Owsley's behalf
RIPPA, SOL A. (1) 1957; re: former student requests recommendation
SCOTT, M.A. 9(1) 1956; re: schooling for daughter in Cambridge
ROBINSON, RONALD (2) 1955-1956; re: position at St. John's College
TATE, ALLEN (1) 1956; re: mentions probable divorce of Tate
SNYDER, LOUIS L. (1) 1956; re: about publication of history book
TEN HOOR, MARTIN (1) 1956; re: news from University of Alabama
THISTLEWAITE, FRANK (2) 1956-1957; re: housing in Cambridge, letter of sympathy to Mrs. Owsley on her husband's death
VANAUKEN,SHELDON (2) 1956; re: VanAuken's thesis
WALTERS, BENNETT (1) 1955; re: Christmas letter
WEINER, BERNARD (1) 1956; re: thank you note
YOUNG, FRANCES A. (1) 1956; re: concerning Fulbright schlorships